KENT TUNEBERG

Rockford, IL

Phone: (815)-621-5184 | **Email**: ktunebe@gmail.com **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kent-tuneberg-59a191320

Portfolio: https://github.com/ktunebe

SUMMARY

Driven and well-rounded full stack web developer with a web development certificate from The University of Wisconsin. Experience in web design utilizing proficiencies in both front-end and back-end programming, with the ability to design, build and maintain web applications. Strong abilities in problem solving and communication with a propensity for on-the-fly critical thinking and adjustment to the changing needs of a team or project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Softwares/Platforms: Express.js, React.js, Node.js, testing, computer science, database theory,

MongoDB, SQL, Git, BootstrapCSS, TailwindCSS **Software Languages:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

PROJECTS

Dungeons and Dragonites

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/ktunebe/dungeons_and_dragonites Deployed Application: https://ktunebe.github.io/dungeons_and_dragonites

- A dungeon crawl game using PokeAPI and D&D 5e API. Use a random Pokémon to fight an endless barrage of D&D monsters.
- Roles: Front end designer for battle page, including animations and modal pop-ups. Dice roll and battle logic Javascript.
- HTML, TailwindCSS, Javascript, API fetch requests

HoliDb

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/ktunebe/holiDB Deployed Application: https://holidb.onrender.com

- A movie search database using the TMDB node package to find movies, tag them by holiday, or even create your own holiday. This uses PostgreSQL and Sequelize to keep track of users, movies and holidays.
- Roles: Front end design and styling, search functionality, Handlebars helper functions...
- HTML, TailwindCSS, Javascript, API fetch requests, Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars, PostgreSQL

Console.blog()

GitHub Repo: https://github.com/ktunebe/magnificent-virtual-compositions-tech-blog Deployed Application: https://mvc-tech-blog-65rn.onrender.com

- A blog allowing users to add posts and comment on others using a Model-View-Controller Framework and a PostgreSQL database.
- Role: Start to finish creation, development and deployment
- HTML, TailwindCSS, Javascript, Express.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Handlebars

CAREER EXPERIENCE

General Dentist Dr. Perry K. Tuneberg and Associates

2015-2023 Rockford, IL

Practiced as a general dentist, which involved diagnosis and treatment of dental conditions, caring for and educating patients, and a strong leadership role in a diverse team environment. Also gained proficiencies in working with dental software and digital radiography.

- Oversaw day-to-day responsibilities of a team of about 25 employees while at times seeing 25-30 patients per day.
- Well-respected member of the dental community and consistent involvement in charitable events and donated dental service programs.
- Winnebago County Dental Society Board Member 2019-2022, including President from 2021-2022

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI February-August 2024

A 24 week intensive program focused on gaining skills in full stack web development. The course covers HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Python, testing, computer science, database theory, MongoDB, SQL, Git, and other modern web skills and technologies.

Doctorate in Dental Medicine (DMD): Southern Illinois University School of Dental Medicine 2011 - 2015

Obtained a DMD degree and a license to practice dentistry.

Bachelor of Arts: Augustana College, Rock Island, IL 2007 - 2011

Graduated cum laude with a major in Biology and a minor in Biochemistry.